战争要来临了
There is a war coming.
可怕的战争
A-a terrible war.
到时会一片混乱
There-there will be chaos.
街上血流成河
Rivers of blood in the streets.
我知道的
I know it!
我能预见到
I-I can see it coming.
是时候了
It's time.
总得有人接替他  那不如就让我来
Somebody has to take over; it might as well be me.
我叫詹姆斯・戈登  我是一名警探
My name's James Gordon. I'm a detective.
我叫布鲁斯・韦恩
My name is Bruce Wayne.
我保证  我会找到凶手的
I promise I will find the man who did this.
站住  不然我开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot!
他是被人栽赃
He was framed
以掩盖真正的凶手
To cover up for the real killer.
再也别回哥谭了
Don't ever come back to Gotham.
他杀了人
He's killed a man.
是哥谭第一黑帮老大卡麦・法尔科内
And he killed him on the orders of Carmine Falcone,
下令让他杀的
biggest crime boss in Gotham.
韦恩夫妇的死
The death of the Waynes
会给我们家族和哥谭带来麻烦
would bring troubled times for our family and Gotham.
马罗尼家族能察觉局势不稳
The Maroni family senses weakness.
吉姆  找你的
Jim, it's for you.
吉姆
Jim.
你好啊  詹姆斯
Hello, James.
老朋友
Old friend.
你一定就是芭芭拉
You must be Barbara.
是的  请进
Yes, please come in.
詹姆斯  你好
James, hi.
我是彼得
I'm Peter.
彼得・汉伯德
Peter... Humboldt.
很高兴终于见到你了
Lovely to meet you at last.
你比我想象中的还漂亮
You're even more beautiful than I imagined.
过奖了
Shush.
很高兴见到你  彼得
Nice to meet you, Peter.
我从来没见过吉姆的朋友
I never get to meet any of Jim's friends,
因为他从不告诉我任何事
'cause he never tells me anything.
-男人嘛  -可不是
- Men. - Don't I know.
要喝杯饮料吗
Would you like a drink?
不用了  他是工作上的朋友
No, uh... he's a work friend.
来找我谈公事
It's a work thing.
我最近刚回哥谭
I'm just recently back in Gotham
就突然想来登门造访一下
and I had an idea to pop by out of the blue.
但显然来的不是时候
But now is clearly not a good time.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
我告诉过你永远别回来
I told you never to come back here!
我知道  我知道  我很抱歉
I know. I know. I-I apologize.
-但我真的有话想跟你说  -不行
- But I-I just wanted to speak with you. - No!
如果法尔科内发现你还活着  他会杀了我们
If Falcone finds out you're alive, he'll kill us both.
我无处可去
I got no place else to go.
哥谭是我的家
Gotham is my home.
我真该杀了你
I should've killed you.
我现在就该开枪打烂你的脑袋
I should put a bullet in your head right now.
你也完全有权利这么做
And you would have every right to do so.
但你不会  吉姆・戈登  因为你是好人
But you won't, Jim Gordon, because you're a good man.
你很可能是哥谭最后一个好人了
You may very well be the last good man in Gotham,
所以我要帮你
and that's why I want to help you.
-我不想要你帮  -或许吧  但你需要我
- I don't want your help. - No, no, but you need it.
那个恶婆娘菲什・穆尼
That vile creature Fish Mooney,
法尔科内阁下  警察...
Don Falcone, the police--
甚至你的搭档都不信任你
not even your own partner trusts you.
他们总会对你隐瞒真相的
They will always hide the truth from you!
但我不会
But not me.
绝不会
Never.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
天知道我有多后悔
God knows I wish I hadn't.
现在就杀了我  不然就相信我
Kill me now or trust me!
我告诉过你战争要来了  吉姆
I told you there's a war coming, Jim.
会死很多人
There will be so many deaths.
很多人
So many.
你想拯救哥谭吗  我可以帮你
You want to save Gotham? I can help you.
我可以给你当秘密特工
I can be your secret agent.
直到法尔科内发现你还活着
Until Falcone finds out you're alive.
没人会去找死人
Nobody looks for a dead man.
这场战争...
This war...
你到底在说什么  为什么会有战争
what are you talking about? Why will there be a war?
你也明白  战争只是政治的另一种手段
Well, as you know, war is just politics by other means.
而政治不就是钱和交易吗
And isn't politics just money, talking?
你指什么
Talking about what?
当然是阿卡姆
Arkham. Of course.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
准备好去吃顶级肋排了吗
Ready for some prime rib tonight?
是啊  先生
I am, sir.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
詹金斯议员
Councilman Jenkins?
-有事吗  -是的
- Can I help you? - Yes, uh,
我是您的选民
I'm one of your constituents.
每次都投票给您
Voted for you every time.
十分感谢  朋友
Well, thank you very much, my friend.
我不会
I don't want to...
过多占用您的宝贵时间
take up too much of your valuable time.
只是想给您看样东西
I just want to show you something.
我很乐意帮助选民
Well, I'm always happy to help constituents,
但你该到办公室找我
but perhaps you can come by my office.
先生  求求您  就一小会儿
Sir, please, just one second.
是这样的
Now...
这个想法我已经思考了
I got the idea for this...
好几年了
years ago.
是我自己设计制造的
Designed and built it myself.
给
Here.
看看
Take a look.
看啊  你就
Go ahead. You...
眼睛对准末端看
just put your eye in the end there.
对了就这样
That's it.
-这什么东西  -您会明白的
- What is that thing? - You'll see.
不不不  不要
No, no, no, no, no, no.
下一个就是你
You're next.
翻译：迷失_绽放   灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   爵士年代蓬蓬裙
翻译：charcie   Silence   木浅薰   夜影章鱼X   哥谭直属
翻译：草草  DustD         特效&后期：宝宝         时间轴：Kallen
时间轴：凭陵新月  最可爱的小胖子       校对&总监：草草
说真的  先生
Honestly, sir,
我真给你投过票
I really did vote for you.
哥谭
第一季  第四集
我在工作
Hey, I'm working.
来了个双尸命案  轮到你了
Caught a double homicide. You're up.
不对吧  阿尔瓦雷斯这一周都没案子
Uh, no way. Alvarez hasn't done a case all week.
该他了
It's his turn.
阿尔瓦雷斯上周加了双倍的班
Alvarez put in double overtime last week.
-戈登  -警监
- Hey, Gordon. - Captain.
市议员罗恩・詹金斯与其助手
Councilman Ron Jenkins and his aide
今晨被发现死在一停车场
were found dead in a parking structure this morning.
还在等法医报告出来
Still waiting on the M.E.'s report,
不过他们的钱包和首饰都不见了
but their wallets and jewelry were missing.
市议员  也许是政治暗杀
A councilman. Maybe it's a political hit.
不会的  没人会去暗杀市议员
Nah, no one hits councilmen.
还不如行贿花的钱少
It's cheaper to bribe 'em.
杀了他们又会有别的废物
You kill 'em and another bum
伸着贪婪的手来顶替他的位子
with his hand out just takes his place.
你们可以去市政厅打探一下
Sniff around city hall if you want.
我敢说  这不过就是不幸的意外
Smart money says this was just wrong place, wrong time.
快干活儿去
Go work it.
你个奴隶主
Slave driver.
别担心  吉姆
Don't worry, Jim.
我知道该从何下手
I know just where to start.
再度茫然若失*
*All at sea again
心内的飓风*
*And now my hurricanes
让这片海下起了倾盆大雨*
*Have brought down this ocean rain
有两下子
She's got talent.
长得也不赖
She's not bad-looking.
够了
That's plenty.
过来  让我好好看看
Come to me so I can take you in.
唱得不错
You sing well.
但要干这活儿  光有一副好嗓子和一张俏脸蛋
For this job, I need more than a pair of nice pipes
可不够
and a pretty face.
我什么都愿意干
I'll do whatever it takes.
这话我爱听  那么
I like hearing that. So...
你喜欢男的还是女的
you like boys or girls?
男的
Boys.
好吧
Fine.
假装我是个男的
Pretend I'm a boy.
引诱我
Seduce me.
至少你会唱歌
Least you can sing.
布奇
Butch?
记上这个
Put a pin in this one.
我们会打给你的
We'll call you.
还凑合  不过继续找
Not bad but keep looking.
不是吧  老大  那可是个美女啊
Really, boss? That's a good-looking girl.
看着我
Look at me.
我要找的不是美女
I ain't looking for no girl.
而是武器
I'm looking for a weapon.
得了  尼奇  别谦虚了
Come on, Nicky, don't be modest.
你就是停车场抢劫小王子
You're the crown prince of parking lot muggers.
没人比你名气大
No one's got a bigger rep.
我在休假好吗
I'm on sabbatical.
我没杀人  不是我风格
I didn't kill no one. That's not my thing.
那你背包里怎么有把匕首
Then why'd you have a shank in your backpack?
防身用的
Protection.
詹金斯议员被杀了
Councilman Jenkins was murdered.
我们知道是你干的
We know it was you.
-我们有证人  -我发誓我没杀人
- We got witnesses. - I swear to God I didn't do it!
他不是我们要找的人  哈维
He's not our guy, Harvey.
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez.
这是什么
What's this?
犯罪现场的证据
Evidence from your crime scene.
刚几个警员送过来的
Couple of unis just dropped it off.
阿卡姆区开发提案
阿卡姆
Arkham.
阿卡姆城
经济适用房
职业培训
零售及服务
重建阿卡姆疯人院
新医学院校区
40英亩  26个街区
40 acres, 26 city blocks.
哥谭市最后一个未开发的大区
The last major undeveloped district in the city of Gotham,
阿卡姆
Arkham.
托马斯和玛莎・韦恩不幸遇害之前
Now, before their untimely and tragic deaths,
他们对这座城市有自己的规划
Thomas and Martha Wayne had a plan for their city,
渐进式的开发计划
a progressive development plan
将阿卡姆的棚户区夷为平地  取而代之的
that would raze Arkham's shanty towns and, in its place,
将是全新的经济适用房
build new, affordable housing
提供给哥谭的贫苦百姓
for Gotham's less fortunate.
那老疯人院呢  市长
What about the old asylum, Mayor?
全拆了  不剩一砖一瓦
Torn down. Brick by brick, if need be.
取而代之的是高端先进的
And in its place, a cutting-edge, state-of-the-art
心理治疗机构
mental health facility.
这是我们城市未来的蓝图
This is a vision for the future of our city.
日前有一对立计划呼声很高
An opposing plan is gaining support recently.
那个计划彻底放弃了疯人院
A plan that would do away with the asylum altogether,
在周围兴建废弃物处理厂
use the surrounding land as a waste disposal site.
这可不行
No.
韦恩夫妇的计划是最有利于本市
No, the Wayne plan is best for this city
最重要的是  也是最有利于哥谭人民的
and, more importantly, for the people of this city.
所以我全力支持这项计划
This is why I am endorsing it.
巴蒙特餐馆
马罗尼阁下
Don Maroni.
很高兴见到您
Pleasure to see you.
谢谢  你怎么样
Thank you. How are you?
请坐  请坐
Please, please, have a seat.
我去拿酒和面包
I'll bring wine and bread.
今天是值得庆祝的日子
Today is a day of celebration.
一桩大买卖就要上门了
A very lucrative deal is coming my way.
地盘  朋友
Land, my friend.
地盘
Land.
那才是真正赚钱的东西
That's where the big money is, huh?
我需要韦恩家族关于阿卡姆的计划
I need information about the Wayne plan for Arkham.
虽说是韦恩的  但现在只是挂名了
Well, it's the Wayne... plan in name only now.
韦恩夫妇死后
When the Waynes died,
法尔科内插了进来  他现在负责计划了
Falcone stepped in. He's backing the plan now.
如果计划能通过  他会做出很多改变
And he stands to make quite a chunk of change, if it passes.
但是詹金斯议员是支持法尔科内的啊
But Councilman Jenkins was backing Falcone's plan.
没错
That's right.
那么他被杀是因为
Then he was killed because...
是因为  警探  出现了一个对立计划
Because, detective, there is an opposing plan.
马罗尼
Maroni.
他是唯一有能力对抗法尔科内的人
He's the only one strong enough to oppose Falcone.
他想插一脚阿卡姆
He's making a play at Arkham.
他们之间有联系吗
Are they related?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
你怎么样
How are you?
新阿卡姆疯人院将以全新的方式
"A new Arkham Asylum will serve the mentally ill of Gotham
服务于哥谭的精神病人
in ways the present asylum never can.
那些饱受疾病折磨的灵魂需要我们的帮助
Those poor, sick souls deserve our help."
这是我妈妈写的
My mother wrote that.
她和我爸爸为建新疯人院努力了好多年
She and my father fought for years to get a new asylum built.
他们认为通过帮助城市最不幸的人
They thought that if they can help the city's least fortunate,
可以让其他人都看到一丝希望
it would show there was hope for everyone.
我真不希望我父母的梦想与他们一同逝去
I just don't want my parents' dream to die with them.
我明白  布鲁斯
I understand that, Bruce.
但这不仅仅是疯人院的事
But this isn't just about the asylum.
如果法尔科内和马罗尼之间真有争斗
If there is a fight between Falcone and Maroni,
这可能会成为引发全市帮派战争的导火索
this could be the spark that ignites a citywide gang war.
无辜者会因此丧命
Innocents will die,
人们对警察的保护还尚存的一点信念
and whatever little faith people have that the police can protect them...
到时都会被击垮
...it will be crushed.
那你得阻止他们
So you have to stop it.
我是戈登
This is Gordon.
是我  我们接到报案
Hey, it's me. We got a call.
市议员泽勒被绑架了
Councilman Zeller's been abducted.
听着  戈登  泽勒是马罗尼的人
Listen, Gordon, Zeller's one of Maroni's guys.
马上到
Be right there.
阿卡姆疯人院
求你...
Please...
不要  我求你了
Don't. I-I'm begging you.
我...
I... aah...!
知道吗
You know...
如果我说了算
if it were up to me,
就会让你死得痛快点  不必搞这么多幺蛾子
this would be over quick, without all the fuss.
我父亲以前常说
My father used to say,
大精若朴
"Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication."
但现在不是我说了算
But it's not up to me.
我的客户明确要求
And my customer specifically asked me to...
要用你的死传个信
send a message.
你也知道俗话怎么说
And you know what they say:
客户永远正确
the customer is always right.
求你了  救命啊
Please... help!
你...你不必这么做
You-you-you-you... you don't have to do this!
救命啊
Help me, somebody!
不  不要
No, wait.
告诉法尔科内  票是可以改的
Tell Falcone I'll change my vote.
我会支持市长的
Hey-hey, I'll-I'll back the mayor.
他让我干什么都行  求你了
I'll do anything he wants, but please, please!
求你了  不
Please... No! Please!
求你了  不要
Please! Please don't!
阿卡姆疯人院
几天内两名市议员被杀
Two councilmen dead in as many days.
肯定不是巧合
Can't be a coincidence.
一定是有什么政治因素
Got to be politics driving this.
他是对的
He was right.
我又没说他不对
I never said he was wrong.
只是不希望他说对罢了
I just wanted him to be.
好了  福尔摩斯
All right, genius,
还有何高见
any other insights?
有  这都是为了阿卡姆提案表决
Yeah. This is about the Arkham vote.
怎么说
How so?
阿卡姆不止是土地交易  而是一场战争
Arkham is more than just a land deal; it's a war
是法尔科内和马罗尼之间的战争
between Falcone and Maroni.
这两个市议员分属不同的阵营
These councilmen were on opposite sides of that war.
那是谁干的
So, who did who?
依我看  是马罗尼先动的手
The way I see it, Maroni struck first.
杀了詹金斯  好让大家投他的票
He had Jenkins killed to change the vote his way.
然后法尔科内以牙还牙
Then Falcone retaliated,
杀了泽勒  把票赢回来
had Zeller killed to change the vote back.
烧尸体就是法尔科内发出的警告
Burning the body was Falcone's way of sending a message.
这事了结之前  我会给市议员
I'll have guards put on all the other councilmen
还有市长增派安保
and the mayor till this plays out.
你不想说说吗
So, you want to tell me?
快说  法尔科内  马罗尼  阿卡姆
Come on. Falcone, Maroni, Arkham?
你怎么突然消息这么灵通
How the hell do you know so much all a sudden?
爱德  查到什么了
Ed, what you got?
这事有点矛盾
I have a paradox for you.
什么
What?
警探  矛盾就是...
Well, a paradox, detective, is when you have...
我知道矛盾是什么意思  机灵鬼
I know what a paradox is, smartass.
怎么矛盾了
What paradox?
这是法医关于詹金斯议员
These are the medical examiner's reports
及其助手被杀一案的尸检报告
on the murders of Councilman Jenkins and his aide.
两名被害人都受到致命刺伤
Both victims sustained fatal puncture wounds
被刺穿眼窝刺入头骨
to the skull via the eye socket.
武器应该是种金属钉
The weapon was some kind of metal spike.
好吧  所以呢
Okay. So?
泽勒议员
Councilman Zeller
也有金属钉留下的伤口
also has wounds from a metal spike.
这也太巧了  不是吗
It's an extremely unlikely coincidence, don't you think?
你是说杀泽勒
So you're saying Zeller,
詹金斯和他助手的凶手是同一个人
Jenkins and the aide were killed by the same person?
看起来是这样  不是吗
It would appear so, wouldn't it?
凶手同时为马罗尼和法尔科内效力
Same killer working for both Maroni and Falcone?
这也太疯狂了
That's nuts.
这种事只会发生在哥谭  走吧
Only in Gotham. Come on.
去哪
Where are we going?
见个朋友
Go see a friend of mine.
你在干什么
What the hell you think you're doing?!
我...
I-I-I-I...
你在偷看  你个人渣
You were snooping, you little worm.
第一天我就跟你说过  在这里
I told you the day I gave you this job that, in here,
你就是瞎子聋子
you don't see nothing, you don't hear nothing.
对不起  老板  请原谅
I'm sorry, sir. I... beg your pardon.
你给我少多管闲事  知道吗
You keep that sniveling nose of yours to yourself, understood?
知道了  老板
Yes, sir.
两盒
Two cartons.
一定是要紧事
Must be important.
-我们在找职业杀手  -是吗
- We're looking for a hit man. - Yeah?
他为谁效力
Which family does he work for?
好几个  是个自由职业者  像你一样
A few. He's an independent type, like you.
这种人已经不多了
Not too many of them still around.
他杀了谁
Who'd he hit?
两个市议员和一个助手
Two city councilmen and an aide.
行凶凶器很特别
Uses some sort of special weapon to kill his victims.
金属钉吗
Steel spike?
大概这么长
About so big?
或许吧
Could be.
-你认识他吗  -听说过
- You know him? - I heard of him.
名叫格拉德韦尔
His name's Gladwell.
很专业
A real pro.
哪能找到他
You know where we can find him?
听人说
Word was
他在市中心兰斯基大楼上班
he works out of the Lansky building in Midtown.
来不来
You coming or what?
还有12个楼层要检查呢
We got 12 more floors to check out.
你干吗这么紧张
What's got you so wound up?
这叫尽职
Maybe I'm just doing my job.
不是  你最近行为古怪
No, you've been acting weird lately,
就好像有事瞒着我
like you got something to hide.
哥谭市警局
GCPD, ma'am.
我们在找一个可能在这里工作的人
We're looking for someone who may work here.
姓格拉德韦尔
Last name Gladwell.
你是说理查德  人力资源部的
Oh, you mean Richard. He works in Human Resources.
理查德没惹什么麻烦吧
Richard's not in any trouble, is he?
他办公桌是哪个
Which desk is his?
倒数第三个
Third one from the back.
格拉德韦尔  理查德・格拉德韦尔  他人呢
Gladwell. Richard Gladwell-- Has anyone seen him?
他刚离开
You just missed him.
-他去哪了  -刚还在呢
- Where'd he go? - He was just here.
可能去后面了
Maybe he headed out the back?
我去看看
I'm gonna go check it out.
你留下  以防他回来
Stay here in case he comes back?
吉姆
Jim!
我有发现
I found something!
看看我在他桌里找到了什么
Look what was in his desk.
是詹金斯和泽勒  我们找对人了
Jenkins and Zeller. We got him.
我就喜欢容易找的人
Man, I love the easy ones.
泽勒议员
詹金斯议员努力推行
激进征税政策
不许动
Freeze!
只是一盒回形针  我以为没人会介意
It's-it's just a box of paperclips. I didn't think anyone would mind.
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. I'm sorry.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
CLM
"C, L, M."
你说这什么意思
What do you think it means?
不知道
I don't know.
没事吧
You all right?
没事
I'm fine.
怎么了
Why?
那个...
Well...
我听到你大喊
I heard screaming.
做了个恶梦
A bad dream.
我有出现在恶梦里吗
Was I in it?
这次没有
Not this time.
阿尔弗雷德  还有其他关于阿卡姆规划的资料吗
Alfred, are there any more files on the Arkham plant?
有
Oh, yeah.
当然有  有数不清的资料  一大堆呢
Absolutely. Untold. Piles of the bloody things.
我想看看
I'd like to see them, please.
所有的资料
All of them.
我可以问问原因吗
And may I ask, uh, why?
我在查这其中的联系
I'm looking for a connection.
市议员被杀和我父母案子之间的联系
Between the councilmen murders and the murders of my parents.
明白了
I see.
都不许动  抢劫了
Nobody move! This is a robbery!
钱都在后面  快去拿
Money's in the back. Go, go!
过来  你也是  过来
Come on-- you, too! Get over there!
走  快点
Let's go, move! Move!
巴蒙特餐馆
闪开  别挡道
Move! Out of the way.
别挡道
Out of my way.
去后面看看
Check the back.
他们把钱拿走了  弗兰基
They got the money, Frankie.
我不是瞎子
I got eyes, don't I?
谢天谢地你们来了
Oh, thank goodness you're here.
他们...他们有枪
They had... they had guns, and...
一枪打在卢的肚子上
and-and Lou... Lou was hit in the stomach.
他还...
Is-is... is he...?
别管卢了
Forget about Lou!
是谁干的
Who did this?
他们都戴着面具
Uh... they had masks.
我看不到脸
I-I couldn't see.
但是你把钱保住了
But you got the money.
是的
Oh, yeah.
我设法把这袋钱藏了起来
I managed to hide this bag,
但剩下的被他们拿走了
but they got the rest.
-对不起  我...  -别紧张
- I'm sorry. I-I-I... - Hey, relax, kid.
这话留着跟老大说吧
Save it for the boss.
你难得提早下班
You're off early for a change.
我想你了
I missed you.
你没事吧
You all right?
加班  晚归  吉姆
Long hours and late nights, Jim.
-都让我很担心  -担心什么
- They make me worry. - About what?
很多事
All kinds of things.
我只是在工作
I'm just doing my job.
是吗
Are you?
什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是我觉得你有事瞒着我
It means I think you have secrets from me.
我讨厌这样
And I hate it.
你要我说什么  芭芭拉  没错
What do you want me to say, Barbara? Yeah.
我有秘密
I have secrets.
那是工作的一部分
It's part of my job.
-这样我才能确保...  -奥斯瓦尔德・科波特是谁
- It's how I make sure... - Who's Oswald Cobblepot?
你怎么知道这个名字的
How do you know that name?
这不重要
Doesn't matter.
他是谁
Who is he?
我没法回答
I can't even begin to answer that.
是不能还是不想
Can't or won't?
是蒙托亚
Montoya.
她来见你了  是吗
She came to see you, didn't she?
是
Yes.
她为什么总来找你
Why does she keep coming to you?
你俩之间什么关系
What is there between you and her?
在我遇见你很多年以前
Years ago, before I was with you...
她和我
she and I
曾经在一起过
were in a relationship.
什么
What?
只维持了一年
It only lasted a year,
然后我跟她分了手  开始了新的生活
and then I-I ended it and moved on.
怎么  她没放下吗
And what, she didn't?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不在乎  好吗  因为你才是那个
I don't care, okay? Because you are the one
我想与之共度余生的人
that I want to spend the rest of my life with.
怎么  你生气了
What, you're angry?
-我当然生气了  -因为她是女人吗
- What do you think? - Because she's a woman?
因为  你骗了我
Because... you lied to me!
好吧  对不起
Okay, I'm sorry.
我应该告诉你的
I should have told you.
法尔科内以为他可以在
Falcone thinks he could hit me
我的地盘上滋事  还能安然无事
in my place of business and get away with it?
他想错了  弗兰基
He's got another thing coming, Frankie.
我要回击
I want to hit him back.
这一次下手要准要狠
This time, where it hurts.
要打在要害上
I want to hit The Mouth.
是时候了
It's time, son.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
还有那小子
Then there's the other thing.
叫他来
Send him over.
你知道我这人该表示感谢的时候  绝不会吝啬
You know I'm a man that shows appreciation when appreciation is due.
是  马罗尼阁下
Yes, Don Maroni.
你昨天的所作所为  我都记在心里了
What you did for me yesterday did not go unnoticed.
谢谢您  先生
Well, thank you, sir.
我只希望我当时能取回
I-I only wish I was able to retrieve the...
-剩下的  -得得得
- retrieve the other half of your... - Bup-bup-bup-bup.
你洗了多久的盘子了
How long you been washing dishes?
-没多久  -从现在起你不用洗了
- Not long. - All right, that ends today.
你升职了  做餐馆经理
You've been promoted to restaurant manager.
这职位刚刚空出来了
The position recently became available.
多谢您  马罗尼阁下
Thank you, Don Maroni.
-我绝不会让您失望  -嗯嗯
- I won't let you down. - Yeah. Yeah.
不客气
You're welcome.
弗兰基  给这小子置办套正装
Frankie, get the kid a suit.
他死了
He's dead.
谁死了
Who?
理查德・格拉德韦尔
Richard Gladwell.
起码本尊是死了
At least, the real one.
派了警员去他的公寓  发现
Sent some unis by his apartment, found a...
有具腐尸藏在里面
moldy old corpse sealed inside.
眼上有刺穿伤  死了五年了
Puncture wound through the eye; been dead five years.
这么长时间才发现他
And no one found him until now?
房东说他按时交房租
Landlord said he paid his rent on time,
平时又安静  简直是完美房客
kept quiet-- the ideal tenant.
也就是说这杀手干掉了格拉德韦尔
So our Hit Man killed this Gladwell
用他的身份作掩护
to use his identity as cover.
而且也成效显著
And it worked, too.
雇员记录  薪金纪录  联系信息
Employee records, payroll, contact information
全是假的
all fake.
除了张脸  我们什么线索都没有
We got nothing but a face.
该死
Damn.
好吧
All right...
这里面肯定有名堂
Well, there's got to be something to this.
这三个字母  你有想法吗
"C-L-M." You got any ideas?
就是浪费时间
It's a complete waste of time.
但这是线索  唯一的线索
It's a lead. Our only lead.
就你这么想
Says you.
你怎么能这么懒
You can't be this lazy.
懒  没准是我办案手法比你高明
Lazy? Maybe I just work smarter than you.
这你想过没
Ever consider that?
是啊  我想过了
Yeah. I considered it.
听着  阿卡姆提案明天就要表决了
Look, this Arkham vote is tomorrow--
如果到那时我们还没抓住这人
we don't find this guy by then...
怎么  会怎样
What? What happens?
最坏的局面  黑帮全面开战
Worst case: a major gang war.
会死人  没准会死很多人
People will die. Maybe a lot of people.
只要抓住这人  就能阻止这一切
We find this guy, we can stop it.
你要去哪
And where are you going?
办案去
To work the case.
你有张良计  我有过墙梯
You got your ways, I got mine.
哈维
Hey, Harvey...
代我向她问好
tell her I said hi.
你听那笑声*
*You hear laughter
响彻大厅*
*Cracking through the halls
让你起舞的欲望*
*It sends you spinning
不可抵挡*
*You have no choice
随着那舞曲*
*Following the footsteps
舞步残破*
*Of a rag doll dance
我们全都*
*We are entranced
意乱情迷*
*Spellbound
意乱*
*Spell...
情迷*
*Bound
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
莉莎
Liza.
你唱歌多久了  莉莎
How long have you been singing, Liza?
没多久
Not long.
你喜欢男的还是女的
You like boys or girls?
男的
Boys.
你想要这份工作吗
So... you want the job, or what?
你还没告诉我是什么工作
Well, you haven't told me what it is yet.
你想拥有权力  金钱和尊重
You want to be a woman with power,
成为像我一样的女人吗
money and respect, like me?
我想是的
I guess. Yeah.
你愿意为了这个目标不惜一切代价吗
Are you willing to do whatever it takes to have it all?
是的  我愿意
Yes. I am.
工作就是这样
That's the job.
引诱我
Seduce me.
什么
What...?
你认为我是在开玩笑吗
You think I'm kidding?
哈维
Harvey...
看到什么喜欢的了吗
you see something you like?
就在眼前
I do now.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
市议员一个接一个地死掉
City councilmen are dropping like flies.
-我听说了  -对生意不好
- I heard. - Bad for business.
你说得没错
You're not wrong.
下手的是个叫格拉德韦尔的家伙  认识吗
The button man's a guy called Gladwell-- you know him?
听说过
Only by reputation.
你能找到他吗
Think you can find him?
只要我有时间  谁都能找到
I can find anyone if I have the time.
问题在于  我有什么好处
The question is, what's in it for me?
算我欠你的
I'll owe you.
好吧  我还是觉得这是在浪费时间
Okay, but I still think it's a waste of time, if you ask me.
法尔科内会找其他人顶上
Falcone'll just get someone to take his place.
他不会放弃的
He's not gonna let this bone go.
为什么
Why's that?
法尔科内输不起这次表决
Falcone cannot afford to lose that vote.
马罗尼只要拿到阿卡姆的一块砖
If Maroni gets even a piece of Arkham,
就证明了众所皆知的事情
it'll only prove what we already know.
那就是  法尔科内老了  不中用了
And that is: Falcone is old and weak.
你看起来挺开心啊
You seem kind of pleased about that.
怎么回事
How come?
法尔科内垮台  你也不好过
Falcone goes down, so do you.
哈维
Harvey...
别担心我
don't you worry about me.
我总有后备计划
I always have a Plan B.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
你好  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
你想干什么
What do you want?
给你提供帮助
To offer you help.
证明你可以信任我
To prove that you can trust me.
会有另一起凶案
There's gonna be another murder.
马罗尼已经派出杀手了
Maroni has put out the hit.
目标是谁
Who's the target?
支持法尔科内的人
Someone backing Falcone's plan.
具体是谁我说不好
Who it is, I can't be certain.
今晚所有的市议员都有警察保护
All the councilmen are under police protection tonight.
警察是很好买通的
There are many ways around the police.
今晚绝对会有人遭刺杀
But the hit will happen tonight--
这我能肯定
that much I can be certain of.
你怎么知道的
How do you know this?
我说过了  警探
I told you, Detective--
哥谭是我的家
Gotham is my home.
给我今晚去执行保护任务的警员名单
I need a list of the officers working police protection tonight.
詹姆斯市长宅邸: 坎波斯  拉赞比  马汀斯
坎波斯  拉赞比  马汀斯
Campos, Lazenby, Martins.
CLM
C-l-m.
我是哈维
It's Harvey.
布洛克  我知道格拉德韦尔下个目标是谁了
Bullock, I found out who Gladwell's next target is.
是市长
It's the mayor.
戈登警探  什么事
Detective Gordon. What's going on?
市长阁下  我认为您可能有危险
Sir, I think your life may be in danger.
-我得带您离开这儿  -什么  不
- I need to get you out of here. - What? No, I...
我不会离开的  有警察保护我呢
I'm not going anywhere-- I got police protection.
-他们走了  -什么
- They're gone. - What?
我刚刚看过了  根本没人在
I just checked, no one's out there.
先生  我觉得有人要来杀你
Sir, I think someone's coming here to kill you.
我得去保险箱拿些东西
I got to get some things from my safe.
先生  我们得马上走了
Sir, we need to go-- now.
我已经在尽快了
I'm moving as fast as I can.
我能带您去什么地方吗
Is there someplace I can take you?
安全的地方
Somewhere you'll be safe?
我们不去警局吗
We're not going to the police station?
我不敢肯定那里会很安全  警察都...
I'm not sure you'll be safe there. The police...
-这个城市是怎么了  -先生
- What the hell is this town com-coming to? - Sir.
好了  好了  我...
All right, all right, I'm...
我姐姐家  在城市另一边
My sister's house. It's across town.
走吧
Let's go.
快走
Go! Go! Go!
还有别的出路吗
Is there another way out?
这边
Here.
他想闯进来
He's trying to get in.
开枪啊  你怎么不打他
Shoot him. Why don't you shoot him?
没办法  他拿了我的枪  快走
He's got my gun. I can't. Go, go, go!
放下武器
Drop it!
放下  否则我开枪了
Drop it or I'll shoot!
你知道人们为什么雇职业杀手吗
You know why they hire a professional?
因为他总能完成任务
'Cause he finishes the job.
你还好吧
How are you?
挺好
Okay.
吉姆  我早该把蒙托亚的事告诉你
Jim, I should've told you about Montoya a long time ago.
-那你为什么没说  -我说不清
- Then why didn't you? - I don't know.
因为她跟你共事
Because she works with you.
因为她是女的
Because she's a woman.
你确定没有别的原因了吗
Are you sure there isn't another reason?
没了  没别的了
No. There's nothing else.
吉姆  我不希望我们之间有秘密
Jim, I don't want there to be any secrets between us.
-我也是  -那就好
- Neither do I. - Good.
那你就告诉我奥斯瓦尔德・科波特是谁
So you'll tell me who Oswald Cobblepot is.
芭芭拉  你为什么就不能忘了这事呢
Damn it, Barbara. Why can't you drop this?
-你为什么不能告诉我他是谁呢  -因为
- Why can't you just tell me who he is? - Because...
这是工作上的事
...it's work.
我知道  但你以前也跟我说过工作的事
I know. But you've told me about your work before.
那是个错误
And that was a mistake.
我不会再犯那种错误了
One I am not going to make again.
好吧
All right. Well...
我不要过这种日子
I'm not gonna live like this.
我不能过这种日子
I can't live like this.
你得做出选择  吉姆
You're gonna have to make a choice, Jim.
要么告诉我  要么放弃我
You either let me in or you let me go.
好了
All right.
我就直说了
I'm going to cut to the chase.
你们两个我都喜欢  但我只能招一个人
I like you both, but I only have one opening.
你挺有才
You've got the talent.
而你...
And you've got...
有点别的东西
...something else.
我无法决定
I can't decide, so...
所以  只能让你俩来替我决定了
you two are going to have to do it for me.
你要我们打架啊
You want us to fight for it?
我什么时候开始上班
So when do I start?
是你啊
It's you.
吓死我们了
Scared us there for a second.
我们做得很棒吧
We do good or what?
简直太漂亮了  朋友们
Excellent work, my friends.
你们很像那么回事
You were very convincing.
那个经理肯定是这么想的
Yeah, I bet that manager sure thought so, huh?
是不是  迪克
Ain't that right, Dickie?
还有哪个馆子你想让我们去抢  尽管说
You got any other joints you want us to rob, let us know.
-报酬丰厚啊  -可不是
- Good money in this. - Yeah, good money.
那是什么
What's that?
我带了奶油甜馅煎饼卷来
Oh, I brought cannoli.
太好了
Oh, yeah!
吃吧
Now, eat up.
这是你们应得的
You guys deserve this.
看啊
Check this out.
真不错
Really good.
太好吃了
Oh, real good.
阿卡姆开发提案表决几周来一直争议不断
The Arkham development vote has been a topic of controversy for weeks.
今天  结果终于出来了
Today we have the results.
我们现在直播詹姆斯市长的新闻发布会
We go live now to Mayor James's press conference.
能小点声吗  我头要疼死了
Do you mind turning that down? My head's killing me.
闭嘴吧
Aw, shut up.
我们辛辛苦苦不就为了这个
This is what we worked for.
这是我们促成的
We did this.
今天的结果难道不是韦恩计划的落空吗
How is today's outcome not simply a failure of the Wayne plan?
这并非任何一个计划的落空
This is not a case of either plan failing.
这是妥协
This is a case of compromise
市长宣布阿卡姆开发提案表决结果
是为了哥谭人民的利益
for what's best for the people of Gotham.
阿卡姆区将同时用作廉价住房
The Arkham district will be developed into both low-cost housing
和我们迫切需要的废弃物处理厂的开发
as well as a much-needed site for waste disposal.
这是吸取了两个计划最好的部分
This is the best of both plans...
合二为一
together in one.
太好了
Yes.
多年来  这座城市只给我们残羹冷炙
For years, this city's been giving us nothing but scraps.
从今往后
But from now on...
from now on...
我们要享用饕餮盛宴了
we feast.
詹姆斯市长  那疯人院呢
Mayor James, what about the asylum?
将会何去何从
What's going to happen to it?
阿卡姆疯人院将进行翻修
Arkham Asylum will be retrofitted
达到当今标准  然后重开
to meet today's standards and reopened.
哥谭需要...不
Gotham needs... No,
哥谭应该
Gotham deserves
有座世界一流的
a world-class treatment facility
精神病院
for the mentally ill.
法尔科内今天受了打击
Falcone took a shot to the body today.
或许再挨几下  他就会倒下了
Maybe a few more will put him on his back.
看来你来的正是时候
Looks like I got you just in time.
我确信  韦恩夫妇
And I know that the Waynes,
如果他们还活着
were they still alive,
也会为我们今日的成就感到自豪
would be proud of what we've been able to accomplish today.
市长把这个新计划说得好像对哥谭有利
The mayor's making this new plan sound like it's good for Gotham.
-但其实不是的  对吗  -的确
- But-but it's not, is it? - No, it's not.
那他为什么要这么做
Then why is he doing it?
他夹在两股厉害的敌对势力之间
He was caught between two very powerful opposing forces.
法尔科内和马罗尼
Falcone and Maroni.
马罗尼威胁到了市长的性命
Maroni threatened the mayor's life.
我猜市长是出于恐惧
Out of fear, I'm guessing,
向马罗尼妥协
the mayor made a compromise
给他分了阿卡姆很大一杯羹
and gave Maroni a huge piece of Arkham.
你指什么
What piece?
马罗尼获批兴建一个废弃物处理厂
Maroni gets to build a waste disposal site
他还拿到了翻修阿卡姆疯人院的合同
and he gets the contract to refurbish Arkham.
法尔科内获批兴建廉价住房
Falcone gets to build a low-income housing project.
听我说
Look...
布鲁斯  我知道这并非你所期待的结果
Bruce, I know it's not the outcome you had hoped for,
但这个妥协
but this compromise
可能避免了很多流血冲突
may have prevented a lot of bloodshed.
甚至阻止了一场战争
It may have even stopped a war.
我父母相信新疯人院能给哥谭带来希望
My parents believed a new asylum would bring hope to Gotham.
这下落空了
Now that's gone.
他们为之努力的一切
Everything they worked for
如今都落入了罪犯之手
is now falling into the hands of criminals.
也不是一切
Not everything.
你还活着
You're alive.
还不迟
It's not too late.
你真这么认为吗
Do you really believe that?
你真的认为哥谭可以获得救赎吗
Do you believe Gotham can be saved?
我相信这值得我们努力
I believe it's worth trying.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com